<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: productivity | Kyle Galloway]]></title>
  <link href="http://kylegalloway.me/categories/productivity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kylegalloway.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-01T16:17:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kylegalloway.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[{"name"=>"Kyle Galloway", "url"=>"https://twitter.com/kylegallowayckg", "email"=>"kyle.galloway.1993@gmail.com"}]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/recurser/jekyll-plugins">Recurser</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prepare for College, and Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://kylegalloway.me/general/productivity/2015/09/01/prepare-for-college-and-life/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://kylegalloway.me/general/productivity/2015/09/01/prepare-for-college-and-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you’re start out at college, many people give you advice (sometimes great; sometimes not so great). This advice often concerns things like use your free time wisely, sit in the front of class, take good notes, don’t stay up too late, etc.</p>

<p>Well, I’m here to be your 1,000,000 visitor. Because most of this advice is true.</p>

<!--end of excerpt-->

<ul>
  <li>Why did I make a C+ in a class where I should have had at least a B+?
    <ul>
      <li>Didn’t study well enough, sat in back of class, lack of sleep (+ 9 am class).</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Why did I make a B+ in a class where I should have had an A+?
    <ul>
      <li>Didn’t study well enough, sat in middle of class, didn’t take good notes.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Why did I make a A+ in a class where I could’ve settled for a B?
    <ul>
      <li>Studied hard, sat in front of class, took good notes, actually studies those notes, was interested in the material.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>The last one is a key example. I was interested in the material. Why? I read over the syllabus and found more information (Google is your friend.) about parts of the class that looked cool.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I struggle to sit and stay attentive when I don’t find the information invigorating. And in school, you will almost always have a class (or several) that you don’t get excited about because they are boring, hard, have a bad teacher, etc. This can usually be overcome by either self-discipline or finding some key part of the class that you are interested in. For me, number 2 works the best.</p>

<p>So, without going too deep into each topic, here are some pieces of advice that I have been using this semester to make better grades.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.wtfprofessor.com/the-ultimate-guide-to-kicking-ass-next-semester/">Ultimate Semester Guide</a></li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>This one has so much information but has been my biggest help so far.</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/habitrpg-review/">Habits</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/morning-routine/">Morning Routine</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/self-study/">Self Study</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/productivity-hacks/">Productivity</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/revision-test-taking-tips/">Test Taking</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/42-things-i-learned-freshman-year/">Freshman Tips</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://collegeinfogeek.com/27-college-tips-i-learned-sophomore-year/">Sophomore Tips</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.wtfprofessor.com/brain-dump/">Prepare for Every Class</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.wtfprofessor.com/how-not-to-blank-on-exam-problems-the-practice-of-active-recall/">Remembering Stuff for Exams</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.wtfprofessor.com/i-feel-like-i-understand-everything-until/">Test Help</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Many of these tips can be used in everyday life. Especially the routines, habits, and techniques you use to make yourself more productive and make it easier to learn things.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>